Support Admin Watch on
kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
I hope I'll end up with
the man I'm with right now.
Oh no!
What if Helena misunderstood
Juanito's note?
We have to talk about
Operation Stop Wedding.
You know, my plan
about you and Helena.
Helena?
Marry me.
I am inviting you all
to a gathering at our
humble home.
I pray that
you may overcome
all the challenges you'll face.
Doña Juanita!
I wanted to ask...
what you thought
of the letter I gave you
the other night?
I apologize.
I haven't read it yet.
We became so busy with
taking care of Helena.
Good morning, Miss.
- Who's that?
- That's Esmeralda
your former housekeeper.
I don't think I need to wish
for anything tonight.
I don't think I need to
wish for anything tonight.
Because my wish just came true.
To see you.
I almost forgot!
He told me in the letter to meet him here.
He might assume I was waiting for him.
Good evening, ladies.
- Good evening, Leandro.
- Good evening, Mother Olivia.
The procession is about to start.
If you're done with your prayers, let's go.
I hope I finish my mission.
Miss Carmelita, please come with me!
Don Alejandro and Doña Soledad caught
Mr. Juanito and Miss Helena together!
What?
Helena?
Carmelita, come over here.
Listen to Father.
He'll only get angry if you don't.
Carmelita!
Is it true that it was your idea
to bring Helena and Juanito closer?
Helena...
Once again, speak the
truth in front of Don Alejandro.
That it was Carmelita who
made you closer to Juanito.
It is true.
Carmelita helped me
and Juanito became closer.
What the heck?
She ratted me out?
After all I did for her
to be close to Juanito.
Now, it's my fault?
Carmelita...
Are they telling the truth?!
Father!
Father...
Carmelita is not to blame.
She is just helping Helena as a friend.
What is happening here, my son?
What is this commotion about?
Your son has broken my trust!
Your son dishonored the
agreement both our families made!
My son... What have you done?
It wasn't Juanito's fault.
It was Carmelita!
Carmelita has nothing to do with it!
I am the reason behind all this.
That was the letter given to me by Juanito.
"I am yours...
...as you are mine."
I am yours as you are mine.
He wrote that for me?
Does that mean, he likes me?!
So that's why he wants
to know my response...
Is this enough evidence
to prove your treachery to my daughter?!
Mind your tongue, Alejandro!
I cannot understand...
Why would Carmelita help Juanito and Helena
end up with each other?
Because she has her own reasons.
Tell them already, Carmelita.
Father...
I am very sorry.
It's all true.
It's true that I pushed Helena
and Juanito to be closer.
And it's also true that
I don't want the wedding to push through.
Because...
Because I still love Leandro.
It is clear...
that there will be no more wedding.
And from this day on, I sever
my family's ties to the Montecarlos.
Mariano...
let's not be too hasty.
We can still fix this
mess, don't you think?
Do not touch me.
I will regret it to my death
if Carmelita gets married
to their unfaithful son.
You have no right to disrespect us!
Maybe you're forgetting I
am the Governor of this land!
- My love?
- Father?!
- My love, what is happening to you?
- Father! Father!
Help us!
- Don Alejandro...
- Stop!
- Stop...
- Call a doctor!
Father?
Carmelita...
Didn't you say Leandro is the reason
why you don't want to
get married to Juanito?
Shouldn't you be happy
that the wedding was cancelled?
Maria's right.
But I can't accept the fact
that I couldn't see Juanito when I want to.
Whenever I want to.
Mother Olivia.
I want to talk to Carmelita.
May you please give us some privacy?
You have to be strong, Carmela.
Because this time...
It's not only Juanito you have to protect.
What?
Your family needs you as well.
What do you mean?
Carmela...
Remember this.
Juanito's death...
Happened on the day of
his wedding to Carmelita.
Even though the wedding was cancelled...
Juanito's life is still in danger.
Not until...
The people behind his murder are exposed.
Juanito's life is still in danger?
Forgive me, Father.
It wasn't my intention
to hurt you and Mother.
And to ruin your friendship
with Don Alejandro.
Is that what happened?
You agreed to your engagement
to Carmelita just for me?
To save my friendship with Alejandro?
That was the truth at first, Father.
But...
It didn't take long for
me to love Carmelita.
Yet you continued talking to Helena.
I do not know what to do anymore, Father.
I don't want to hurt anyone's feelings.
Remember, son.
A true gentleman knows how
to stand up for his decisions.
And to be true to his heart.
Do not worry, Father.
I will speak to Don
Alejandro and fix all of this.
This mess is between me and Alejandro.
As the head of this family, I
should be the one to fix this.
But Father...
My son...
No matter what you've done...
My love for you will never be gone.
Josefina!
May I be the one to take this to Father?
Make sure you ask for forgiveness.
So that he may feel better.
Father?
Father, forgive me--
Get out!
Father, I'm sorry that
the wedding got cancelled.
I didn't mean it.
I apologize.
Father...
I'm really sorry.
Please forgive me.
I said get out!
I don't want to see your face!
Get out now!
Carmelita...
I'm so sorry, Father.
Get out!
Soledad.
Miss, you must eat.
You didn't eat breakfast earlier as well.
I don't have an appetite.
Miss, there's something you must know.
It's about the Flores family.
What is it?
But you have to eat first before I tell
you the important news you need to hear.
Say it first. Go on.
I heard that
Miss Helena and Miss Natasha
are going to Madrid tonight.
What?
She's running away after
blaming everything on me?
I thought we were friends.
Take this away, Theresita.
I'm going to see Helena.
What?
Wait, Miss. I'm coming with you.
Mr. Sergio took Mr. Leandro
to Cavite earlier this morning.
Meanwhile...
Miss Natasha went to see Mother Olivia.
Miss Helena has been staying
in her room since last night.
She hasn't eaten anything yet.
I know Helena is suffering more.
Maybe she can't accept that
Juanito fell in love with me.
But, wait...
In the original diary...
Juanito really loved Helena.
And Carmelita's love was unrequited.
What happened?
Why was it flipped?
Why did Juanito fall for me?
I need to speak to Mother Olivia.
- Miss, thank goodness you came out!
- What are you doing here?
I'm asking you, Carmelita.
What are you doing here?
Why are you leaving?
What is my purpose here?
You already took Juanito from me!
Our wedding was cancelled.
His heart belongs to you!
And I can't accept...
that it was you he chose.
Wait, when did Juanito choose me?
I know you've been together
at the library in Santo Tomas.
And I know he was
waiting for you at the plaza.
He stopped writing to me.
Because he started to fall for you.
Here!
This opened my eyes to the truth
that Juanito could never love me!
Because he's already in love with you!
Helena, wait...
Yes.
You took Juanito from me.
And I swear to you...
You will never end up with each other.
It's enough for me that
your wedding was cancelled.
Miss...
What's written in the diary
was completely changed.
Now I know why Juanito fell for Carmelita.
He fell in love.
Not with Carmelita...
But with me.
Is Helena the one behind Juanito's murder?
But they loved each other.
It is also possible that Helena
had Juanito killed for marrying Carmelita.
And she doesn't want
anyone else to have him.
She's a bit selfish too.
From now on, I need to
keep a close eye on Helena.
Angelito!
Miss!
Nice to see you here.
I slipped out.
Don't worry, Miss.
Father attended a meeting
held at the town this morning.
While Sergio is in Cavite.
But Mother...
She's resting in her bedroom.
She was deeply saddened by what happened.
I'm really sorry for
everything that happened.
You don't have to apologize, Miss.
We are actually grateful
you spoke for Juanito's behalf.
If not, he's gonna take all the blame.
Good thing I have someone
on my side in times like this.
Where is Juanito?
I knew you were looking for him.
I didn't understand what he meant but...
He told me he's getting air
in the place where it all began.
The place where it all began?
Is there such a thing?
My brother Juanito is a bit of a poet.
You should get used to it.
To see the place where it all started...
Juanito.
How did you know where I am?
"The place where it all began."
It was decided here that
we were to be married.
And I guess, we're also here to...
End everything.
Juanito...
- The truth is...
- Don't worry, Carmelita.
You don't need to tell me...
Your answer to the poem I gave you.
Thank you, Carmelita.
Because you gave me
a chance to be with you.
And to know you.
I wish for your happiness.
Together with Leandro.
It's been the talk of the town
how Mr. Juanito was caught
with his other woman.
Meanwhile,
they've been saying you are in love.
With an unknown man.
Good morning, Carmelita.
I was about to leave for Cavite.
But I thought it's not
right for me to leave you.
Especially now that you're
dealing with a lot of things.
I know...
How heavy your heart is.
Because of the incident with your father.
That is why I'm gonna talk to him.
And tell him...
that we weren't doing anything wrong.
You'd do that?
And once the tension dies down...
I will ask your father for
your hand in marriage.
Carmelita.
Once again,
I want to hear the words
you said the other night.
Your hearts must be dancing with joy.
I am happy for the two of you.
Let's head to the dining room.
Carmelita, just wait a moment.
I will just talk to your father.
I just want to thank you.
Because you saved my family from danger.
It seems only yesterday
when I almost went crazy
thinking about
how I will survive in this era.
There's no TV, laptop,
cellphone, or video games.
But now...
I'm too busy thinking about
all the stupid things I did.
Why didn't I tell Juanito my true feelings?
I never really learn.
I should've learned my lesson with James.
I didn't have the guts
to confess my feelings.
And now...
I had to let go of Juanito too.
Miss, can I take your time for a moment?
It's clear to me that you're
doing everything you can
to forget Mr. Juanito.
But I believe that your friendship
shouldn't be disregarded.
That's why, I think you
should still keep this.
Laura sent that box earlier this morning.
She told me you needed to
have that since it belongs to you.
If only I was able to read this.
I wouldn't have hurt Juanito.
Carmelita!
Why the worried faces?
Carmelita, do not panic.
We also learned this from Eduardo just now.
What is it?
Eduardo said there's a
commotion at Hacienda Alfonso.
What?
The Governor General ordered
to search all of the Alfonso's property.
They will also arrest Don Mariano.
If they find proof
that he is helping and
supporting the rebels
who are fighting the government.
And if he is truly behind
Don Diosdado Valdez' murder.
Impossible!
Don Mariano and his family are good people!
We should ask help from Father!
Let's inform him!
Father is attending a
meeting in another town.
He'll be back later tonight.
But we sent someone to tell him the news.
I have to help them. Wait!
Carmelita, will you please calm down?
Carmelita...
- Move quickly!
- Spare my children, please, I beg you!
Do not hurt my family.
- No!
- Father!
- Stop!
- Carmelita! Carmelita!
- Carmelita! Don't!
- Sir!
Sir! Please let her go!
Please forgive my sister.
She's still young.
You look familiar to me.
You're a...
student of Mother Superior Olivia,
right?
Yes, sir!
Very well.
Your sister is too young to understand
whether it's appropriate to
intervene on official matters.
General Seleno!
We found a crate of weapons
hidden in their storeroom.
And there's plenty of rice
stocked inside their granary.
My eldest son, Sergio, is
also a general like yourself.
It is normal for us to have
guns inside our home.
But these kind of guns must
be stored inside the camp.
Unless he plans on using
them somewhere else?
Are you accusing my son of treason?
If not, then explain yourself!
Why are you hoarding rice like this?
This certain type of rice...
is known to have a stable shelf life.
Rain or shine, it doesn't go bad easily.
Why do I need to explain myself to you?
You won't even listen to me.
Just take me to court.
I will fight for the truth there!
You are being arrested!
There's nothing we can do for a criminal
who is unashamed of his sins!
My father is innocent!
So you cannot arrest him!
Although I am assigned to Manila...
The Governor General instructed me
to investigate your family.
My family did nothing wrong.
Not all bad deeds are easily seen.
Sometimes, you must scrutinize
the newly-harvested rice...
In order to discover the
stones and dirt mixed into it.
You will all be placed under house arrest!
- Do you understand?!
- No! Our family is innocent!
Juanito!
Mother! Mother!
General.
Please excuse us.
I will take my daughters home.
Go home now.
- We're leaving. We're going home.
- Carmelita, let's go.
- Carmelita, come on...
- We must leave, Carmelita!
Go. Leave this place.
Let's ask Father for
forgiveness tomorrow morning.
Whatever the reason, leaving
home like that was wrong.
My ladies, there's something you must know.
According to Eduardo,
General Seleno took Don Mariano
as a captive and went to Manila.
He also learned that he will be
imprisoned at Fuerte de Santiago
while his case is being heard.
Are you sure about that?
Don Mariano is facing heavy charges.
I'm sure he knows a lot of
lawyers willing to help his case.
Unfortunately,
Heneral Seleno designated
Mr. Ocampo as his lawyer
since no other lawyer would
take Don Mariano's case.
Mr. Ocampo from the other town?
He can't defend his clients properly!
Don Mariano's in danger.
I will talk to Father.
About what?
If you're gonna appeal for the Alfonsos,
I think it's better for
you to shut your mouth...
And go to bed.
But Father, I cannot rest
knowing Don Mariano's life is in danger.
Let's help them. I know you can save Don--
And why would I do that?
We have no relations to one another.
I do not care about him.
And I don't give a damn about his family.
Weren't you old friends?
You have history together, don't you?
Will you just let him be?
Father!
Alejandro! What do you think you're doing?!
You shouldn't have slapped your daughter!
Don't you forget that I
am the man of this house.
I did everything to protect
the name of our family.
But because of your meddling
with General Seleno's work,
and working together
with Juanito and Helena
to stop your wedding...
You brought shame and danger to our family!
Let go of me, Soledad.
Alejandro!
Carmelita?
My Dad never raised his hand against me.
Didn't expect to experience it here.
Here is your luggage, Miss.
I prepared all the things you will need
for a few days in Manila.
Thank you.
Do everything you can to help Don Mariano.
But... what about Father?
Don't you worry.
Mother Olivia told Father
that you'll be staying
at the convent at Sugbu.
To get away from the problems
and ponder your thoughts.
So he knows...
You're gonna be at the convent in Sugbu
Thank you.
Carmelita, please be careful.
Don't let any friends of
father recognize you in Manila.
We talked to Don Buencamino.
He's the one in-charge of the ship.
He promised to keep your
journey to Manila a secret.
And don't you worry.
Mother Olivia will meet you there.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
By the way...
Someone wants to come with you.
Good day, ladies.
Wait, how did you escape the civil guards?
Eduardo helped me.
He knows the way in
and out of our property.
Don Buencamino.
Ladies and good sir.
The ship will sail in a minute.
The two of you stay here,
until a room becomes vacant for the lady.
Thank you.
Miss, are you...
Carmelita, you don't have to avoid me.
I already accepted that my
love for you is unrequited.
Sometimes, I wish I wouldn't have known...
That your heart belongs to someone else.
I wish...
I didn't hold on to hope...
That you will fall in love with me too.
And I wish...
I was brave enough to
tell you my true feelings
right from the start.
You're wrong, Juanito.
It's you that I want.
But I'm afraid of what might
happen if I tell you the truth.
Juanito, you don't need to
hide your tears from me.
Just for a little while.
Thank you, Carmelita.
I didn't expect you to
go against your father
just to help us.
Are you only doing this
because you have grown close
to my brother?
This my plan
so that we can attend
Father's hearing
without anyone recognizing us.
This is my wife,
and these are my friends
from England.
I have a witness
who can testify that he is planning
treason against the government.
We need your father.
We must save him.
If I come with you and escape,
it's as good as a confession
of my crime.
Carmela, prepare yourself.
A lot of things and people
will be taken in place of Juanito.
Destiny is being rewritten.